Inventory of the California Department of Industrial Relations. Division of Statistics and Research Records, 1913 - 1984
Labor Archives and Research Center
California Department of Industrial Relations. Division of Statistics and Research Records,
1913 - 1984
1986/031
California Department of Industrial Relations. Division of Statistics and Research
39 cubic feet
San Francisco State University. Labor Archives Research Center San Francisco, California 94132
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Introduction
This collection was donated to the Labor Archives and Research Center in 1986 by the library of the Division of Statistics and Research, California Department of Industrial Relations. The collection consisted of 100 cubic feet of periodicals, pamphlets, books and assorted materials collected in their library's stand-up files. The restriction on the donation stated the collection was to remain intact for five years in the event the donor needed to retrieve any documents. Processing began in 1994, at which point the Labor Archives sorted the collection, keeping materials under its regular collection policy and offering other materials to institutions or discarding it. This reduced the collection to its present size.
Scope and Content
This collection can be used to supplement and enhance research in LARC's primary collections. Although the earliest publication is 1913, the bulk is from the 1920s, 1930s and 1940s. A large amount of the material addresses working conditions in California, but most of the pamphlets are from agencies in the U.S. Department of Labor and the WPA and are national in scope.
There is a large collection on women's work, beginning in 1921 and continuing through World War II and the post-war reconversion period. Another subject well represented is the Great Depression. Pamphlets on the "New Deal" and from the WPA cover the subjects of agriculture, migratory workers, unemployment, relief programs, and job training. The enactment of unemployment insurance is documented along with many alternative proposals considered in the 1930s. Material on occupational safety dates from 1922 and includes pamphlets on safety for youths and women. Early concerns about the hazards of radiation and pesticides can also be found. California economic conditions, unemployment and labor force statistics are represented. Labor material includes convention proceedings and publications from the California organizations of the AFL and the CIO.
There are five large runs of periodicals: The American Federationist, 1935 - 1959 (broken run); California State Federation of Labor Weekly Newsletter, 1953 - 1959; California Safety News, 1917 - 1975 (from December 1933 to March 1940, this serial includes many articles on safety during the construction of the Golden Gate Bridge and the San Francisco- Oakland Bay Bridge); California Employment and Payrolls, 1938 -1976; and Monthly Labor Review, 1916 - 1977. This last collection is the largest, held in 14 record boxes (14 cubic feet). All of these periodicals have been relocated to LARC's Periodical Collection.
Books found in this collection are listed in the Box/Folder List following a notation that they have been relocated to LARC's Book Collection.
The remaining materials are arranged alphabetically by subject. Wherever possible the list follows the subject headings established in the LARC's Ephemera Files and is cross-referenced on the Box/Folder List when these Ephemera Files hold additional material on the same subject. All pamphlets are listed by title, author and date of publication. When a folder holds a single pamphlet, it is listed on the Box/Folder List; if there is more than one, there is a notation referring the researcher to a listing in the Appendix.
Collection Guide
Container List
*: Relocated to LARC's Periodical Collection
**: Relocated to LARC's Book Collection
- AGED (Box 1/1)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication) See also: LABOR FORCE--CALIFORNIA--SEASONAL WORKERS LARC Ephemera Files, 1930 - 1945 (Box-folder 1/2)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--CALIFORNIA, 1942, U. S. Congress, Senate. (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Hearings...Investigation of Western
  - Farm Labor Conditions
  - Holdings: Part 1 (Sacramento); Part 2 (Los Angeles)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--FAMILY FARM, (undated) (Box-folder 1/4)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--EMERGENCY COMMITTEE TO AID FARMWORKERS, INC., 1962 (Box-folder 1/5)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--MIGRATION (See appendix for U.S. Congress Hearings) See also: WORLD WAR II--MIGRATION, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 1/6)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--MIGRATION, 1941 (Box-folder 2/1)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--MIGRATION, 1941 (Box-folder 2/2)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--MIGRATORY WORKERS (See appendix for U.S. Congress Hearings), 1961 - 1973 (Box-folder 2/3)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--MIGRATORY WORKERS, 1961 - 1973 (Box-folder 3/1)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--NATIONAL ADVISORY COMMITTEE ON FARM LABOR, 1961 - 1966 (Box-folder 3/2)
- AGRICULTURAL LABOR--NATIONAL SHARECROPPERS FUND, 1965 - 1970 (Box-folder 3/3)
- AGRICULTURE--WPA DIVISION OF SOCIAL RESEARCH (See appendix for pamphlets listed numerically by number), 1937 - 1940 (Box-folder 3/4)
- AGRICULTURE--WPA DIVISION OF SOCIAL RESEARCH, 1937 - 1940 (Box-folder 3/5)
- AGRICULTURE--WPA DIVISION OF SOCIAL RESEARCH, 1937 - 1940 (Box-folder 4/1)
- AGRICULTURE--WPA DIVISION OF SOCIAL RESEARCH, 1937 - 1940 (Box-folder 4/2)
- AGRICULTURE--WPA NATIONAL RESEARCH PROJECT (See appendix for pamphlets listed numerically by number), 1937 - 1939 (Box-folder 4/3)
- AGRICULTURE--WPA NATIONAL RESEARCH PROJECT, 1937 - 1939 (Box-folder 4/4)
- AGRICULTURE--WPA NATIONAL RESEARCH PROJECT, 1937 - 1939 (Box-folder 5/1)
- AGRICULTURE--WPA NATIONAL RESEARCH PROJECT, 1937 - 1939 (Box-folder 5/2)
- ALCOHOLISM--UNION COMPANY PLANS, 1964 - 1979 (Box-folder 5/3)
- ANTI-TRUST LAWS AND UNIONS, 1953 - 1961 (Box-folder 5/4)
- *AMERICAN FEDERATION OF LABOR
  - The American Federationist, official publication of the AFL and the AFL-CIO, August 1935 - June 1940, January 1947 - December 1959
- CALIFORNIA STATE FEDERATION OF LABOR CONVENTION PROCEEDINGS 14th (1913) to 41st (1940) See also: LARC Ephemera Files, 1914- 1940 (Box Box 6)
- CALIFORNIA STATE FEDERATION OF LABOR CONVENTION PROCEEDINGS 42nd (1941) to 47th (1944), 1941- 1944 (Box Box 7)
- CALIFORNIA STATE FEDERATION OF LABOR CONVENTION PROCEEDINGS 48th (1950) to 54th (1956), 1950-1956 (Box Box 8)
- CALIFORNIA STATE FEDERATION OF LABOR CONVENTION PROCEEDINGS 55th (1957) to 57th (1959), 1957-1959 (Box Box 9)
  - CALIFORNIA STATE FEDERATION OF LABOR YEARBOOKS STATE LABOR MANUALS 1919,1933, 1935, 1936
  - CALIFORNIA STATE FEDERATION OF LABOR YEARBOOK 1937, 1939
- *California State Federation of Labor Weekly Newsletter (6 bound volumes)1953-1959
- **COMMUNICATION WORKERS OF AMERICA
  - Barbash, Jack, Unions and Telephones: the Story of the Communication Workers of America, Harper Brothers 1957
- COMMUNISM IN UNIONS See also: LARC Ephemera Files, 1948, 1954 (Box-folder 10/1)
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--CALIFORNIA STATE INDUSTRIAL UNION COUNCIL--CONVENTION See also: LARC Ephemera Files, 1939 (Box-folder 10/2)
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--CALIFORNIA CIO COUNCIL--CONVENTIONS CONVENTION REPORTS, 1943, 1945, 1946, 1947 (Box-folder 10/3)
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--CALIFORNIA INDUSTRIAL UNION COUNCIL-- CONSTITUTION, 1952 (Box-folder 10/4)
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--CALIFORNIA INDUSTRIAL UNION COUNCIL-- CONVENTION PROCEEDINGS1950, 1953, 1955 (Box 10/5)
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION (AFL-CIO)--CALIFORNIA INDUSTRIAL UNION COUNCIL--CONVENTION 1956 1957, 1958 (Statement of Policy only) (Box-folder 10/6)
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--CALIFORNIA INDUSTRIAL UNION COUNCIL-- YEARBOOK, 1951 - 1953 (Box-folder 10/7)
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--PUBLICATIONS (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by publication number) (Box 11/1)
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--PUBLICATIONS California CIO Facts and Figures, 1942 - 1946 (Box-folder 11/2)
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--PUBLICATIONS (Box 11/3)
  - California Industrial Union Council Newsletter ( 2 folders) 1951-1958
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--PUBLICATIONS (Box 11/4)
  - California Industrial Union Council Newsletter (2 folders) 1951-1958
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--PUBLICATIONS (Box 11/5)
  - California Industrial Union Factual Ammunition 1950-1952
- CONGRESS OF INDUSTRIAL ORGANIZATION--PUBLICATIONS (Box 11/6)
  - California CIO Council of Political Education, SCOPE 1957-1958
- **ECONOMIC CONDITIONS, 1923 - 1932
  (Books listed alphabetically by author)
  - California State Planning Board, Economic and Industrial Survey of the San Francisco Bay Area, by Robert D. Calkins and Walter D. Hoadley, Jr., 1941
  - Graves, Lloyd M., The Great Depression and Beyond, The Brookmire Economic Service, 1932
  - U.S. President. Conference on Unemployment, Business Cycles and Unemployment, McGraw-Hill Book Co., 1923
  - U.S. President. Conference on Unemployment, Recent Economic Changes in the United States, Vols. I and II, McGraw-Hill Book Co., 1929
- ECONOMIC CONDITIONS--CALIFORNIA--POST WORLD WAR II--PUBLICATION Postwar California, Vol. 1, (1944)--University of California (Box-folder 12/1)
- ECONOMIC CONDITIONS--CALIFORNIA--POST WORLD WAR II-PUBLICATION (Box 12/2)
  - Postwar California, Vol. 1, (1944)--University of California 1944
- ECONOMIC CONDITIONS--CALIFORNIA--POST WORLD WAR II--PUBLICATION (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Postwar California, Vol. 2, (1945)--University of California 1945
- ECONOMIC CONDITIONS--CALIFORNIA--POST WORLD WAR II--PUBLICATION (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Postwar California, Vol. 2, (1945)--University of California 1945
- ECONOMIC CONDITIONS--CALIFORNIA--POST WORLD WAR II--PUBLICATION (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Postwar California, Vol. 3, (1945 - 1946), University of California 1945-1946
- ECONOMIC SECURITY PROGRAMS ("NEW DEAL") (See appendix for pamphlets listed alphabetically by title), 1933 - 1935 (Box-folder 12/6)
- EDUCATION AND LABOR EDUCATION (See Appendix for pamphlets listed alphabetically by author) See also: LARC Ephemera Files, 1949 - 1961 (Box-folder 13/1)
- HEALTH CARE--AGRICULTURAL, 1942 (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Cost of Medical Care in the Agricultural Workers Health and Medical Association, by William Goldner 1941
- HEALTH CARE--UNION PLANS See also: HEALTH INSURANCE, LARC Ephemera Files, 1946 - 1977 (Box-folder 13/3)
- HEALTH INSURANCE (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication) See also: HEALTH CARE, 1939 - 1970 (Box-folder 13/4)
- HEALTH INSURANCE--COMPULSORY, 1947 (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Compulsory Health Insurance, by Elizabeth W. Wilson, National Industrial Conference Board 1947
- HEALTH INSURANCE--KAISER/PERMANENTE, 1960 - 1964 (Box-folder 13/6)
- HOURS OF WORK (Box 13/7)
  - Studies of the Effects of Long Working Hours, by Max D. Kossoris 1944
- HOURS OF WORK--FLEXTIME AND ALTERNATIVE WORK SCHEDULES1971-1984 (Box 13/8)
- INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication) See also: LARC Ephemera Files (Box 14/1)
- INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS The Management Almanac, 1943 - 1945 (Box-folder 14/2)
- INTERNATIONAL LABOUR OFFICE (ILO) (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1922 - 1969 (Box-folder 14/3)
- LABOR FORCE (See appendix for pamphlets listed numerically by bulletin number), 1927 - 1942 (Box-folder 14/4)
- LABOR FORCE, 1937 (Box-folder 14/5)
  - The Labor Supply in the United States: Occupational Statistics of the 1930 Census Tabulated by Class of Work and Industry, as well as by Sex, Race, and Age Groups
- LABOR FORCE--CALIFORNIA--SEASONAL WORKERS See also: UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA California Employmentand Payrolls, 1939, 1942 (Box-folder 14/6)
- LABOR FORCE--CALIFORNIA--WAR MANPOWER COMMISSION--"LABOR SUPPLY PROBLEMS...ALAMEDA", 1943 (Box-folder 14/7)
- LABOR FORCE--CALIFORNIA--WAR MANPOWER COMMISSION--PRESS RELEASE, SHIP REPAIR IN NORTHERN CALIFORNIA, 1945 (Box-folder 14/8)
- LABOR FORCE--CALIFORNIA--WORLD WAR II (Box 15/1)
- LABOR FORCE--CALIFORNIA--WORLD WAR II--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical) (See Appendix for title of Reports) 1943-1945 (Box 15/2)
- LABOR FORCE--CALIFORNIA--WORLD WAR II--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical) 1943-1945 (Box 15/3)
- LABOR FORCE--CALIFORNIA--WORLD WAR II--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical) 1943-1945 (Box 15/4)
- LABOR FORCE--CALIFORNIA--WORLD WAR II--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical) 1943-1945 (Box 15/5)
- LABOR FORCE--CALIFORNIA--WORLD WAR II--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical) 1943-1945 (Box 15/6)
- LABOR HISTORY See also: LARC Ephemera Files, 1929 - 1971 (Box-folder 15/7)
- LABOR LEGISLATION DECISIONS OF THE COURTS AND OPINIONS AFFECTING LABOR See also: LARC Ephemera Files, 1914 - 1932 (Box-folder 16/1)
- LABOR LEGISLATION DECISIONS OF THE COURTS AND OPINIONS AFFECTING LABOR, 1914 - 1932 (Box-folder 16/2)
- LABOR LEGISLATION DECISIONS OF THE COURTS AND OPINIONS AFFECTING LABOR, 1914 - 1932 (Box-folder 16/3)
- LOCAL INDEPENDENT UNIONS (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1960 - 1963 (Box-folder 17/1)
- MANUALS FOR SHOP STEWARDS, BUSINESS AGENTS, ETC. (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1955 - 1971 (Box-folder 17/2)
- **MEATCUTTERS BUTCHER WORKMEN OF NORTH AMERICA, AMALGAMATED...
  - Brody, David, The Butcher Workmen: a Study of Unionization, Harvard University Press, 1964
  - Medical Care, see: HEALTH CARE
- MEMBERSHIP ATTITUDE SURVEYS AND STUDIES, 1939 - 1967 (Box-folder 17/3)
- *Monthly Labor Review, U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1916-1977
- "New Deal" see: ECONOMIC SECURITY PROGRAMS
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY, 1922 (Box-folder 17/4)
  - The Physician in Industry: A Symposium, National Industrial Conference Board, Special Report No. 22 See also: LARC Ephemera Files 1922
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--AGRICULTURE, 1949 - 1972 (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Safety on the Farm, California Farm Bureau Federation (undated)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--AGRICULTURE--CHILD LABOR, 1967 - 1969 (Box-folder 17/6)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--AUTOMATION, 1964 (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Health and Safety Aspects of Automation and Technological Change: A Collection of Abstracts, 1956 to 1962, Prepared by the Int'l. Labour Office, Geneva, Switzerland, U.S. Dept. of Labor 1964
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--BIBLIOGRAPHY, 1900 - 1943 (Box-folder 17/8)
  - Bibliography of Industrial Hygiene, 1900-1943, U.S. Public Health Service, 1945 1945
- *OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--CA
  - California Safety News, V. 1 (1917) - V. 58 (1975)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--CA (Box 18/1)
  - Labor Occupational Health Program M ONITOR, 1974-1981 1974-1981
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--HAZARDS--PESTICIDES--DBCP HEARINGS 1977 (Box 18/2)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--HAZARDS--PESTICIDES--DBCP HEARINGS 1977 (Box 18/3)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--HAZARDS--PESTICIDES--DBCP HEARINGS 1977 (Box 19/1)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--HAZARDS--PESTICIDES--DBCP HEARINGS 1977 (Box 19/2)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--HAZARDS--RADIATION (See appendix for studies and pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1949 - 1968 (Box-folder 19/3)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--LABOR STATEMENTS (See appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1947, 1973 (Box-folder 19/4)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--MACHINERY AND BOILERMAKERS, 1920, 1951 (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Accidents and Accident Prevention in Machine Building, by Lucian W. Chaney, U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1919 1919
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--MENTAL HEALTH (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1958, 1966 (Box-folder 20/1)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--PULP PAPER WORKERS, 1955 - 1956 (Box-folder 20/2)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--PULP PAPER WORKERS-- (Box 20/3)
  - INJURY FREQUENCY REPORTS 1950-1968
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--SAN FRANCISCO CITY COUNTY WORKERS 1950 (Box 20/4)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--SAN FRANCISCO--DRY CLEANING ESTABLISHMENTS, 1940 (Box-folder 20/5)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--SEAMEN (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1928 - 1954 (Box-folder 20/6)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--SHIPYARD WORKERS (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1943 - 1977 (Box-folder 20/7)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--STATISTICAL METHODS (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1920 - 1944 (Box-folder 21/1)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--WOMEN (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication) See also: WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II--SAFETY, 1920 - 1977 (Box-folder 21/2)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--YOUNG WORKERS (See Appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1951 - 1966 (Box-folder 21/3)
- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY--YOUNG WORKERS U.S. DEPT. OF LABOR, CHILDREN'S BUREAU AND BUREAU OF LABOR STANDARDS, 1941 - 1966 (Box-folder 21/4)
  - Occupational Hazards to Young Workers, Reports Nos. 1-18 (See Appendix for title of Reports)
- SOCIAL SECURITY (Box 22/1)
  - Postwar Social Security Problems in California 1944
- Teamsters, Int'l. Brotherhood of... See: LARC Ephemera Files
- TEAMSTERS, CENTRAL CONFERENCE OF...Address of Dave Beck, General President, 1954 (Box-folder 22/2)
- TEAMSTERS, WESTERN CONFERENCE OF...--PROCEEDINGS, 13th Meeting 1949, 14th Meeting 1950, 1949, 1950 (Box-folder 22/3)
- **TRADE UNIONS
- **Barbash, Jack, Unions and Their Leadership, Harper Brothers, 1959
- **Catlin, Warren B., The Labor Problem in the United States and Great Britain, Harper Brothers, 1926
- TRADE UNIONS--FOREIGN (Box 22/4)
- **UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT (See appendix for book titles listed alphabetically by author)
- **Graham, Frank D., Abolition of Unemployment, The.... Princeton University Press, 1932. 98p.
- **Gordon, Margaret S., The Economics of Welfare Policies, Columbia University Press, 1963. 159p.
- **International Labour Office, Unemployment Problems in 1931, Studies and Reports, Series C, No. 16, Geneva, 1931. 180p.
- **International Labor Office, Unemployment Problems in the United States, by H. B. Butler, Studies and Reports, Series C, No. 17, Geneva, 1931. 112p.
- **Johns Hopkins University, Department of History, Political Economy, and Political Science, Unemployment and American Trade Unions, by D. P. Smelser, 1919. 154p.
- **Lewisohn, Sam A., et al, Can Business Prevent Unemployment, Alfred A. Knopf, 1925. 226p.
- **University of Pennsylvania, Wharton School of Finance and Commerce, Case Studies of Unemployment, Marion Elderton, Editor, 1931. 418p. See also: UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT (See appendix for pamphlets listed alphabetically by title) See also: LARC Ephemera Files--UNEMPLOYMENT WOMEN WORKERS, 1916 - 1929 (Box-folder 23/1)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT, 1930 - 1935 (Box-folder 23/2)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT, 1936 - 1950 (Box-folder 23/3)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT, 1960 - 1980 (Box-folder 23/4)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA, 1914 - 1940 (Box-folder 23/5)
- *UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA
  - California Employment and Payrolls, 1939-1976
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical) (See Appendix for listing of Reports), 1935 (Box-folder 24/1)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical), 1935 (Box-folder 24/2)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical), 1936 (Box-folder 24/3)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical), 1936 (Box-folder 24/4)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical), 1937 - 38 (Box-folder 24/5)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA--PUBLICATIONS (Statistical) (Box 24/6)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA--YOUTH AUTHORITY WARDS, PAROLEES, 1960 - 1981 (Box-folder 25/1)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--RELIEF PROGRAMS, 1915 - 1930 (Box-folder 25/2)
  (Pamphlets listed alphabetically by title)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--RELIEF PROGRAMS, 1931 - 1942 (Box-folder 25/3)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--RELIEF PROGRAMS--CALIFORNIA 1915, 1940 (Box-folder 25/4)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--RELIEF PROGRAMS--CALIFORNIA, 1942 (Box-folder 25/5)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--RELIEF PROGRAMS--SENATE HEARINGS, 1933 (Box-folder 26/1)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--TECHNOLOGICAL CHANGE--WPA NATIONAL RESEARCH PROJECT (See appendix for listing of pamphlets), 1938-1940 (Box-folder 26/2)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--TECHNOLOGICAL CHANGE--WPA NATIONAL RESEARCH PROJECT, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 26/3)
- UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--TECHNOLOGICAL CHANGE--WPA NATIONAL RESEARCH PROJECT, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 26/4)
- UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE (See appendix for pamphlets listed alphabetically by title), 1922 - 1935 (Box-folder 27/1)
- UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE, 1922 - 1935 (Box-folder 27/2)
- UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE, 1922 - 1935 (Box-folder 27/3)
- UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE--BIBLIOGRAPHY, 1931 (Box-folder 27/4)
- UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE--CALIFORNIA--WORK SHARING UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE, 1978 (Box-folder 28/1)
- UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE--UNEMPLOYMENT RESERVE PROGRAMS (Pamphlets listed alphabetically by title), 1930 - 1933 (Box-folder 28/2)
- **UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE--UNEMPLOYMENT RESERVES PLANS
  - Hansen, Alvin H. and Merrill G. Murray, A New Plan for Unemployment Reserves: Based on Minnesota Employment Data, University of Minnesota, Employment Stabilization Research Institute, 1933
- UNEMPLOYMENT INSURANCE--UNION STATEMENTS, 1930 - 1932 (Box-folder 28/3)
- UNION CONSTITUTION PROVISIONS, 1959 - 1965 (Box-folder 28/4)
- UNION DEMOCRACY (See appendix for listing of pamphlets), 1953 - 1960 (Box-folder 28/5)
- UNION LABEL See also: LARC Ephemera Files, 1951 (and undated) (Box-folder 28/6)
- Wages--CA, See also: UNEMPLOYMENT/EMPLOYMENT--CALIFORNIA California Employment andPayrolls
- WAGES--MINIMUM WAGE See also: LARC Ephemera Files, 1960 (Box-folder 28/7)
- WAGES--SAN FRANCISCO, 1948 (Box-folder 28/8)
  - Wartime and Postwar Earnings: San Francisco, 1941-1946, by May Goringe Luck, University of California Press, 1948
- WAGES HOURS, 1929 - 1932 (Box-folder 28/9)
- WAGES HOURS--FAIR LABOR STANDARDS ACT, 1938 (Box-folder 29/1)
- WHITE COLLAR WORKERS, ORGANIZATION OF..., 1951-1984 (Box-folder 29/2)
- WOMEN WORKERS (See appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication) See also: LARC Ephemera Files, 1921 - 1925 (Box-folder 29/3)
- WOMEN WORKERS, 1926 - 1930 (Box-folder 29/4)
- WOMEN WORKER (See appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1931 - 1933 (Box-folder 30/1)
- WOMEN WORKERS, 1934 - 1936 (Box-folder 30/2)
- WOMEN WORKERS See also: WOMEN WORKERS--WORLD WAR II LARC Ephemera Files, 1937 - 1950 (Box-folder 30/3)
- WOMEN WORKERS, 1951 - 1960 (Box-folder 30/4)
- WOMEN WORKERS (See appendix for pamphlets listed by date of publication), 1961 - 1967 (Box-folder 31/1)
- WOMEN WORKERS, 1969 - 1970 (Box-folder 31/2)
- WOMEN WORKERS, 1971 - 1984 (Box-folder 31/3)
- WOMEN WORKERS--CALIFORNIA, 1951, 1983 (Box-folder 32/1)
- WOMEN WORKERS--CALIFORNIA--ADVISORY COMMISSION ON THE STATUS OF WOMEN -- CONFERENCES, 1966 (Box-folder 32/2)
- WOMEN WORKERS--CALIFORNIA--ADVISORY COMMISSION ON THE STATUS OF WOMEN-- CONFERENCES, 1966 (Box-folder 32/3)
- WOMEN WORKERS--CALIFORNIA--ADVISORY COMMISSION ON THE STATUS OF WOMEN-- REPORTS, 1967 - 1973 (Box-folder 32/4)
- WOMEN WORKERS--CALIFORNIA--ADVISORY COMMISSION ON THE STATUS OF WOMEN --CALIFORNIA WOMAN, 1975 - 1978 (Box-folder 32/5)
- WOMEN WORKERS--CALIFORNIA--ADVISORY COMMISSION ON THE STATUS OF WOMEN --CALIFORNIA WOMAN, 1979 - 1981 (Box-folder 33/1)
- WOMEN WORKERS--CALIFORNIA--ADVISORY COMMISSION ON THE STATUS OF WOMEN --CALIFORNIA WOMAN, 1982 - 1985 (Box-folder 33/2)
- WOMEN WORKERS--CALIFORNIA--EMPLOYMENT DEVELOPMENT DEPT.--WOMEN AT WORK IN CALIFORNIA, 1973, 1974, 1978 (Box-folder 33/3)
- WOMEN WORKERS--FACT SHEETS (Index in first of two folders), 1964 - 1974 (Box-folder 33/4)
- WOMEN WORKERS--FACT SHEETS, 1964 - 1974 (Box-folder 33/5)
- WOMEN WORKERS--FACT SHEETS, 1963 - 1970 (Box-folder 33/6)
  - Background Facts on Women Workers in the United States, U. S. Department of Labor, Women's Bureau
- WOMEN WORKERS--FACT SHEETS--HOUSEHOLD WORKERS, 1965 - 1972 (Box-folder 33/7)
- WOMEN WORKERS--OLDER WOMEN, 1934 - 1958 (Box-folder 34/1)